Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series IV. RG Youth and Early Development 1941 - 1965, 1 box total
  - E. Twelfth Grade/Roosevelt High 1958 - 1959
    - 4. Five issues of The Roosevelt Standard (Box 013)
      - 1959 June 4
        (graduation issue), w/ notice of Senior Prom, Sallie Quan & RG's Citizenship Awards (w/ photo), SQ & RG's Scholarship Awards (Western & Harvard) (w/photo), Senior Train Ride, RG's 4th place finish in, State Golf Meet & RG's Athlete of the Year Award (w/ photo).
    - 5. Copy of Gems, Vol. 3 (Minneapolis English Teachers' Club) 1959 May, w/ RG's first published poem, "Communion" (Box 013)
    - 6. Roosevelt Graduation Materials 1959 June (Box 013)
      - Letter regarding RG Certificate of Merit in Merit Scholarship Program
      - Program for 1959 Roosevelt Commencement Exercises
      - RG graduation photo
      - RG Second Athletic Award ("Letter") in Basketball
      - RG Third Athletic Award ("Letter") in Golf
      - Program for Roosevelt Award Day 1959 June 3, (w/ six citations of RG)
    - 7. Nine Yearbook Photos of RG & High School Sweetheart Sallie Quan 1958 - 1959 (Box 013)
      - Roosevelt Basketball Team (RG No. 15)
      - Basketball Coach Wayne Courtney gives RG an earful
      - Basketball action, Washburn game (RG No. 12)
      - Basketball Team after loss to archrival South in District 17 (Minneapolis) Championship Game
      - Roosevelt Golf Team (RG front row, second from right)
      - RG & Sallie Quan, chosen "Most Likely to Succeed"
      - Roosevelt Humanities Club (w/ RG & SQ)
      - Sagamore (Yearbook) Staff (RG sports editor)
      - SQ entering Auditorium
  - F. RG/Sallie Quan Materials 1958 - 1977
    - 1. Photo of SQ before Roosevelt Senior Prom 1959 June 5 (Box 013)
    - 2. SQ tss. of four SQ poems (Box 013)
      - "ONCE I COLLECTED FIGURINES"
        Written 1958, pub. in Gems, Vol. 3 (Minneapolis English Teachers' Club, May 1959).
      - Poem beginning "Never knew what lonesome meant.. ."
      - "Thoughts" 1959
      - "Who Am I ?" 1959
    - 3. RG autobiographical chronicles & poems written after breakup w/ SQ 1959 Nov, (RG tss, 1960, 66 pp. total) (NOT FOR PUBLICATION!) (Box 013)
      - "listen"
      - "STRAWBERRY DAY"
      - "NEW YEAR'S EVE"
      - "IN PLACE OF OBSERVATION"
      - "BABY"
      - poem beginning "verbless words..."
      - poem beginning "strange/seeing you there..."
      - "WALTER"
    - 4. Photos of RG, SQ & RG's daughter Amy in Lanesville (Box 013)
      Occurred in Massachusetts in November 1977 during brief reunion (after almost 20 years).
  - G. RG Papers from Harvard Freshman Year 1959 - 1960
    - 1. "THE EFFECTS OF THE FALL ON ADAM AND EVE" 1960 Mar 1, (RG ts.) (Box 013)
    - 2. "LOVE AND THE DUKE" 1960 Mar 14, (RG ts.) (Box 013)
    - 3. "THE CONVENT OF THE GRANDE CHARTREUSE IN WORDSWORTH AND ARNOLD" 1960 Mar 31, (RG ts.) (Box 013)
    - 4. "DISCIPLINE vs. OPPORTUNITY IN THE EUROPEANS" 1960 May 5, (RG ts.) (Box 013)
  - H. Harvard Sophomore - Senior Years 1962 - 1965
    - 1. Gordon Cairnie materials (Box 013)
      - Article regarding Grolier Book Shop & GC from The Christian Science Monitor 1970 July 6, (w/ photo of GC)
      - Copy of The Other End of the Couch
        From The Carthage Press, 1964, and contains Poems for Gordon Cairnie, w/ RG's "Song" (noted in Monitor article).
    - 2. Four photos from wedding of RG & Emily Ann Lord at Unitarian Church in Newton, Massachusetts 1963 May 26 (Box 013)
    - 3. RG poems from Harvard Sophomore Year 1962 - 1963 (Box 013)
      - 10 poems from Robert Lowell's Advanced Poetry Writing course 1963 Spring
      - "A Sort Of Renewal", published in Dusk Road Games (Pym-Randall Press) 1963, (RG holograph)
      - "Goodbye", pub. in Dusk Road Games, (RG ts. w/ Emily Lord linoleum block print of Watertown trolley)
    - 4. RG papers from Harvard Senior Year 1964 - 1965 (Box 013)
      - "The Self-Made/ Pioneer" 1964 Oct 30, (RG ts.)
      - "TWO CONCEPTS OF COMPETENCE" 1964 Dec 4, (RG ts.)
      - "DEATH AND ORGANIC FORM IN WHITMAN'S 'Out Of The Cradle Endlessly Rocking'" 1965 Spring, (RG ts.)
    - 5. Various evaluations of RG's work at Harvard College (Box 013)
      - Two comments by Robert Lowell re RG poems written in RL's Advanced Poetry Writing course, (RG ts.)
      - Spring 1963 & Spring 1965
      - Comments by two 'anonymous' readers on RG's Senior Honors Thesis on William Carlos Williams' prosody, (lost?)
      - RG's final grade report 1965 Spring
    - 6. Schofield Andrews, Jr., Secretary of the Faculty of Arts and Sciences, notices to RG of award of Harvard Monthly Prize as "student in the most advanced course in English composition who shows the greatest literary promise" (Box 013)
      - SA ts. letter to RG 1964 Apr 29, For the year 1963 - 1964. (w/ clipping re same from Minneapolis Tribune)
      - SA ts. letter to RG 1965 June 10
        Notice for the year 1964 - 1965.
    - 7. Schofield Andrews, Jr. notice to RG of award of Roger Conant Hatch Prize for Lyric Poetry for 1964-1965 for poem "The Minnesota Soldiers' Home in Autumn", (pub. in RG's Dusk Road Games, Pym-Randall Press, 1967) (Box 013)
      - SA ts. letter to RG 1965 May 24
      - Broadside of "The Minnesota Soldiers' Home in Autumn"
- Series V. RG Talks (Conversations/Readings/Lectures/Workshops) 1981 - 1998, Dated chronologized and counted (by pages of text, if text) - 1½ boxes
  The Media materials require at least two weeks' advance notice to use in order to allow staff time to have use copies made from the original items.
  - A. Audiotapes of RG Talks
    - 1. RG Reading w/ Lyn Hejinian, St. Mark's Poetry Project, NYC 1981 Apr 8, (2 tapes) (no transcript) (Box 014)
      - RG reads poems from SENTENCES (Whale Cloth Press, 1978), all of Oakland (Tuumba Press, 1980), Drafts of poems in A Day At The Beach (Roof Books, 1985)
    - 2. RG Lecture "Measure's Halloween", New College of California, San Francisco 1981 Oct 15, (1 tape) (no transcript but see material discussed, in V.C. below) (Box 014)
    - 3. RG Series of Talks "Language/Site/World", Intersection, San Francisco 1982 Nov 22 - 1983 Jan 24, (5 tapes) (Box 014)
      - Talk One, 1982 Nov 22, (1 tape) (no transcript)
      - Talk Two, 1982 Nov 29, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript of whole talk, & RG ts. of excerpt pub. in Bob Perelman's Writing/Talks (So. Ill. U. Press, 1984) + RG notes for whole series in V.C. below)
      - Talk Three, 1982 Dec 6, (1 tape) (no transcript)
      - Talk Four, 1982 Dec 13 & 1983 Jan 24, (interrupted) (2 tapes) (no transcript)
    - 4. RG Reading & Discussion of A Day At The Beach, 544 Natoma Street, San Francisco, 1983 Jan 13 & 1983 Jan 20, (2 tapes) (Box 014)
      - 1st Session 1983 Jan 13, (1 tape) (no transcript)
      - 2nd Session 1983 Jan 20, (1 tape) (RG ts. transcript/ draft w/ RG holograph annotations & RG final ts. version (unpublished) called "WRITING TIMES" + RG holograph notes for session in V.C. below)
    - 5. RG Discussion w/ Joanne Kyger & David Bromige, "Projectivist Sources", Intersection, San Francisco 1983 Sept 19, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 6. RG Reading, Canessa Park, San Francisco 1985, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
      - RG reads draft of Attention (Institute of Further Studies, 1985) & poems from Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986), (begins w/ simultaneous reading w/ Alastair Johnston of different trans. of Heidegger's "On The Essence Of Truth")
    - 7. RG Conversation w/ Tom Clark, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1985 Sept 13, (2 tapes) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 8. RG Reading w/ David Bromige, The Lab, San Francisco 1985 Aug 30, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
      - RG reads poems included (& pretty good poems not included) in Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986)
    - 9. RG Reading from Phantom Anthems, Canessa Park, San Francisco 1985 Dec 1, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 10. RG Conversation w/ Tom Clark, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1986 Jan, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript draft & RG final ts. version called "A CONVERSATION WITH TOM CLARK" in V.C. below) (unpublished) (Box 014)
    - 11. RG Reading w/ Kenneth Irby, Intersection (?), San Francisco 1986 Mar, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
      - RG reads poems from Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986)
    - 12. RG Conversation w/ David Bromige, Sebastopol, CA 1986 April 24, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript draft in V.C. below) (unpublished) (Box 014)
    - 13. RG Conversation w/ David Bromige, Sebastopol, CA 1986 May 7, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 14. RG Conversation w/ David Bromige, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1986 July 3, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript draft, DB notes on/annotations to RG holograph draft & RG final ts. version called "DAVID BROMIGE / ROBERT GRENIER" in V.C. below) (excerpt pub. in Witz, Spring 1994) (Box 014)
    - 15. RG Conversation w/ Alastair Johnston, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Feb 12, (1 tape) (AJ/RG holograph draft transcript, RG ts. draft w/ AJ annotations, RG final ts. & pub. version (in DARK AGES CLASP THE DAISY ROOT, March 1991) in V.C. below) (Box 014)
    - 16. RG Conversation w/ Joanne Kyger, Bolinas, CA 1987 July 11, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript in V.C. below) (unpublished) (Box 014)
    - 17. RG Reading at Detroit Institute of Arts 1987 Oct 23, (1 tape, w/ Anselm Hollo at DIA, 1987 Mar 22, reverse side) (no transcript) (Box 014)
      - RG reads 'review' of Alice Notley's Parts Of A Wedding, 'review' of Anselm Hollo's Pick Up The House, Oakland (Tuumba Press, 1980) & poems from Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986)
    - 18. RG Reading at Woodland Pattern Book Center, Milwaukee, WI 1987 Oct 25, (1 tape) (Box 014)
      - RG reads 'reviews' of Alice Notley's Parts Of A Wedding, Anselm Hollo's Pick Up The House, "Midday" section of A Day At The Beach (Roof Books, 1985) & poems from Phantom Anthems (0 Books, 1986), (RG holograph transcript in V.C. below) (unpublished)
    - 19. RG Conversation w/ Kit Robinson & Kathleen Frumkin, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Nov 21, (1 tape) (RG holograph transcript in V.C. below) (unpublished) (Box 014)
    - 20. RG Conversation w/ Kit Robinson, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Dec 20, (2 tapes) (KR ts./RG holograph transcript draft & KR ts. near-final version w/ RG holograph corrections in V.C. below) (unpublished) (Box 014)
    - 21. RG Discussion w/ Anselm Hollo, "The Poem As Translation", New College of California, San Francisco 1988 Nov 28, (2 tapes) (no transcript) (videotape in V.B. below) (Box 014)
    - 22. RG Conversation w/ Joanne Kyger, Bolinas, CA 1989 Apr 22, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 23. RG Reading at Woodland Pattern Book Center, Milwaukee, WI 1989 Sept 23, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 24. RG Workshop Class "Spiritual Topographies", Naropa Institute, Boulder, CO, 1992 July 6 & 1992 July 9, (4 tapes) (no transcript) (various materials for workshop in V.C. below) (Box 014)
    - 25. RG Conversation w/ Rebecca Bush, Naropa Institute, Boulder, CO 1992 July 8, (1 tape) (RB print-out transcript Draft w/ RG annotations, RG ts. transcript & pub. version called "INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT GRENIER" (in The Little Magazine, Vol. 20, 1994) in V.ca. below) (Box 014)
    - 26. RG Lecture "Drawing Form Nature", Naropa Institute, Boulder, CO 1992 July 9, (1 tape) (various materials in preparatory to lecture in V.C. below) (Box 014)
    - 27. RG Talk at The Frost Place, Franconia, NH 1993 Aug 6, (1 tape) (Stephen Dignazio transcript drafts w/ RG holograph corrections/additions & pub. version called "GRENIER TALK: FROST PLACE, FRANCONIA, NH, 08.06.93" (in :that:, 2nd Series, 1996) in V.C. below) (Box 014)
    - 28. RG Talk "Realizing Things", SUNY/Buffalo, Buffalo, NY 1998 Oct 22, (2 tapes) (no transcript) (Box 014)
  - B. Videotapes of RG Talks
    - 1. RG Reading/Discussion w/ Anselm Hollo, Canessa Park, San Francisco 1988 Nov 27, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
    - 2. RG Discussion w/ Anselm Hollo, "The Poem As Translation", New College of California, San Francisco 1988 Nov 28, (1 tape) (no transcript) (audiotape in V.A. above) (Box 014)
    - 3. RG Talking About Larry Eigner, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1996 Feb 28, (1 tape) (no transcript) (Box 014)
  - C. Transcripts & Published Versions of RG Talks (& Related Items)
    - 1. RG Lecture "Measure's Halloween", New College of California, San Francisco 1981 Oct 15, Materials Read/Discussed (4 pp. total) (no transcript) (Box 015)
      - Photo of RG at Gopher Boys' State 1958 June, (xerox)
      - Anon. (13-15th cent.) poem "Maiden in the mor", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - Robert Creeley poem "They Say", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - Charles Olson poem "...phalaropes/piled up on Thatchers", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - Louis Zukofsky poem "AZURE", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - RG poem "s o m e o l d g u y s w i t h s c y t h e s", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - William Carlos Williams poem "An Eternity", (xerox)
      - Gertrude Stein text "ROAST POTATOES", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - Robert Creeley piece "Is a door/for-but/who enters", (xerox of RG ts.)
      - RG poems "saids" & "roams", (xerox of RG tss.)
    - 2. RG Series of Talks "Language/Site/World", Intersection, San Francisco 1982 Nov 22 - 1983 Jan 24 (Box 015)
      - Envelope containing RG series description/announcement & RG notes toward four talks, (77 pp. total)
      - RG holograph transcript of Talk Two, 1982 Nov 29, (tape in V.A. above) (95 pp. total)
      - RG holograph letter to Bob Perelman, regarding selection of material for BP's Writing/Talks (So. Ill. U. Press, 1985) 1983 July 29, (xerox) (8 pp. total)
      - RG ts. of excerpt from Talk Two, called "LANGUAGE/SITE/ WORLD", Pub. in Bob Perelman's Writing/Talks (So. Ill. U. Press, 1985) (20 pp. total)
    - 3. RG Discussion of A Day At The Beach, 544 Natoma Street, San Francisco, 1983 Jan 20 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph notes toward talk/discussion, "3 times", (1 p. total)
      - RG ts. draft transcript of talk/discussion, called "WRITING TIMES", w/ RG holograph annotations (tape in V.A. above) (35 pp. total)
      - RG ts. final version of "WRITING TIMES", (unpublished) (37 pp. total)
    - 4. RG Conversation w/ Tom Clark, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1986 Jan (Box 015)
      - RG holograph draft transcript of conversation, (tape in V.A. above) (89 pp. total)
      - RG ts. final version called "A CONVERSATION WITH TOM CLARK / ROBERT GRENIER", (unpublished) (47 pp. total)
    - 5. RG Conversation w/ Alastair Johnston, Berkeley 1986 Feb 21, (audiotape lost) (Box 015)
      - Issue of The Ampersand, Vol. 6, No. 2 1986 Apr
        Containing AJ transcript of conversation "TYPEWRITER v. TYPEFACE/...AN INTERVIEW WITH POET ROBERT GRENIER..." w/ photo of RG's SENTENCES (Whale Cloth Press, 1978) (17 pp. total)
      - RG xerox enlargements of poems from SENTENCES for use on back cover of issue of The Ampersand, (2 pp. total)
    - 6. RG Conversation w/ David Bromige, Sebastopol, CA 1986 Apr 24 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph transcript called "A CONVERSATION WITH DAVID BROMIGE", (tape in V.A. above) (unpublished) (56 pp. total)
    - 7. RG Conversation w/ David Bromige, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1986 July 3 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph transcript called "CONVERSATION WITH DAVID BROMIGE", (tape in V.A. above) (79 pp. total)
      - DB annotations on RG holograph draft, (incorporated by RG into RG final ts. version) (81 pp. total)
      - RG final ts. version called "DAVID BROMIGE / ROBERT GRENIER" 1986 July 3, (excerpt pub. in Witz, Spring 1994) (54 pp. total)
      - History of the making of Witz excerpt from first part of RG final ts. version of conversation 1986 July 3, (36 pp. total)
        - RG ts. letter to Chris Reiner, editor/publisher of Witz, 1994 Feb 24, (xerox) returning first set of proofs, re punctuation & corrections generally
        - First set of proofs, marked by DB & RG, (xerox)
        - CR holograph letter to RG, enclosing second set of proofs, marked by RG 1994 Mar 1, (xerox)
        - CR holograph letter to RG, 1994 Mar 11
        - CR holograph letter to RG, enclosing Issue of Witz, Vol. 2, No. 2 (Spring 1994) 1994 Apr 7
    - 8. RG Conversation w/ Alastair Johnston, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Feb 12 (Box 015)
      - AJ/RG draft transcript (begins as AJ print-out called "ALASTAIR JOHNSTON CHAT WITH BOB GRENIER, WINTER 1986", (w/RG holograph annotations, continues to end as RG holograph transcript) (tape in V.A. above) (39 pp. total)
      - RG ts. draft transcript called "A CONVERSATION WITH ALASTAIR JOHNSTON / ROBERT GRENIER", w/ corrections/ revisions by AJ & RG in holograph (23 pp. total)
      - RG final ts. version 1987 Apr, (22 pp. total)
      - Issue of DARK AGES CLASP THE DAISY ROOT, No. 5, "A CONVERSATION WITH ALASTAIR JOHNSTON / ROBERT GRENIER" 1991 Mar, xeroxed from RG final ts. version (44 pp. total), ed. Andrew Schelling & Benjamin Friedlander
    - 9. RG Conversation w/ Joanne Kyger, Bolinas, CA, 1987 July 11 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph transcript called "CONVERSATION WITH JOANNE KYGER (July 11/87)", (tape in V.A. above) (unpublished) (74 pp. total)
    - 10. RG Reading at Woodland Pattern Book Center, Milwaukee, WI 1987 Oct 25 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph transcript called "RG / Woodland Pattern / October 25/87", (tape in V.A. above) (unpublished) (43 pp. total)
    - 11. RG Conversation w/ Kit Robinson & Kathleen Frumkin, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Nov 21 (Box 015)
      - RG holograph transcript called "KIT ROBINSON / KF / RG (November 21/87)", (tape in V.A. above) (unpublished) (93 pp. total)
    - 12. RG Conversation w/ Kit Robinson, 2338 McGee Avenue, Berkeley 1987 Dec 20 (Box 015)
      - KR/RG draft transcript (begins as KR print-out called "KIT ROBINSON / ROBERT GRENIER (December 20, 1987)", w/ RG holograph annotations, continues to end as RG holograph transcript) (tape in V.A. above) (107 pp. total)
      - KR print-out second-stage draft w/ RG holograph changes & Joanne Kyger poem "BOB GRENIER'S BLACK BERRY PIE", (xerox) w/ JK holograph inscription (unpublished) (76 pp. total) 1987 Dec 13
    - 13. RG Telephone Interview w/ Chris Brandt, Bolinas, CA/ Vancouver, BC 1992 Mar 10, (tape in CB possession?) (Box 015)
      - CB holograph Christmas card to RG, 1992, enclosing
      - CB holograph transcript of exchange w/ RG called "TELEPHONE INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT GRENIER 1992 Mar 10, (xerox) SUBJECT: 'STRIPED CANVAS' " w/ RG holograph corrections (unpublished?) (11 pp. total)
    - 14. Materials for RG Workshop "SPIRITUAL TOPOGRAPHIES", Naropa Institute, 1992 July 6 & 1992 July 9, (tape in V.A. above) (62 pp. total) (Box 015)
      - Workshop description, (xerox of RG ts.)
      - RG selections from WATERS/PLACES/A TIME by Larry Eigner, ed. RG (Black Sparrow, 1983), (xerox)
      - RG selections from JUST SPACE by Joanne Kyger (Black Sparrow 1991), (xerox)
      - RG selections from Kenneth Irby tss. of KI poems (later collected in CALL STEPS, Station Hill/Tansy 1992
    - 15. Materials for RG Lecture "DRAWING FORM NATURE", Naropa Institute 1992 July 9), (tape in V.A. above) (80 pp. total) (Box 015)
      - RG holograph title page, (w/ two versions of title)
      - RG holograph preparatory notes & extracts
      - Louis Zukofsky essay "AN OBJECTIVE", (xerox)
      - Extract from Gertrude Stein's Lucy Church Amiably, (xerox)
      - Page of butterfly-wing 'letters', (color xerox)
      - Page from Robert Creeley's Pieces, (xerox)
      - Emerson's essays "The Poet" & "Nature", (xerox)
      - Extracts from Novalis / A Romantic's Theory of Language and Poetry by Kristin Pfefferkorn, (xerox)
      - Extract from Henri Corbin, The Cycle of Avicennan Recitals, (xerox)
      - Extract from John Elder, Imagining The Earth, (xerox)
    - 16. RG Conversation w/ Rebecca Bush, Naropa Institute, Boulder, CO 1992 July 8, (tape in V.A. above) (Box 015)
      - RB print-out letter to RG, proposing publication of conversation & RG poems in The Little Magazine 1993 Dec 7, enclosing
      - RB print-out draft transcript called "INTERVIEW WITH ROBERT GRENIER", w/ extensive RG holograph annotations (18 pp. total)
      - RG final ts. version, (starting over from tape) (27 pp. total)
      - Page proofs for The Little Magazine version w/ RG holograph corrections, (23 pp. total)
      - RG selection of RG holograph drawing poems, to accompany interview in The Little Magazine, called "BJELDANES SERIES", (black/white xerox of RG original 4-color poems) w/ RG holograph title page (9 pp. total)
      - Issue of The Little Magazine, Vol. 20 1994, w/ RG "BJELDANES SERIES" & Interview (197 pp. total)
    - 17. RG Talk at The Frost Place, Franconia, NH 1993 Aug 6 (Box 015)
      - Stephen Dignazio holograph letter to RG, enclosing tape of talk 1995 Oct 9, (tape in V.A. above) )
      - SD ts. letter to RG 1995 Oct 21, enclosing
      - SD print-out of SD "'in progress' transcription" of "GRENIER TALK: FROST PLACE, FRANCONIA NH, 08.06.93", w/ extensive RG holograph changes (xerox) (21 pp. total)
      - SD holograph letter to RG 1996 Jan 8, enclosing
      - SD second-stage print-out transcript of talk w/ RG holograph changes, (xerox) (18 pp. total)
      - Issue of :that:, 2nd Series, No. 1 (1996) w/ "GRENIER TALK: FROST PLACE, FRANCONIA NH, 08.06.93", Includes two RG color drawing poems as front/back covers (20 pp. total)
- Series VI. RG Critical Writings 1960 - 1998, Being notes, papers, essays, reviews, verse commentaries, speculative jottings, etc., dated/ chronologized and counted (by pages of text) in folders. 1 box.
  - A. Harvard College Papers 1960 - 1965
    - 1. RG ts. of "A 'WATTSONIAN' ANALYSIS OF SCIENCE SINCE SCHOLASTICISM", 1960 May 16, (10 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 2. RG ts. of "J. D. SALINGER: NEGATIVE and AFFIRMATIVE",1960 May 19, (7 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 3. RG ts. of "DEATH AND POE: THE IMAGINATION'S LIMITED DESCENT",1962 Nov 20, (6 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 4. RG ts. of "PRIMITIVE MAN'S CONCEPTION OF MANA: ITS ROLE IN THE ORIGIN AND FUNCTION OF RELIGION",1963 Jan, (18 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 5. RG ts. of "MEANING AND EXISTENCE: SOME ONTOLOGICAL REFLECTIONS ON HUSSERL'S TRANSCENDENTAL EPOCHE",1963 Fall Term, (15 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 6. RG ts. of "Here And Now: Locale And The Development Toward Form In The Poetry Of William Carlos Williams", 1963 Spring Term, (21 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 7. RG ts. of "WILLIAM CARLOS WILLIAMS: An Approach To His Character", 1965 Jan 18, (72 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 8. Georg Trakl Materials (Independent Study, 1964 - 1965) (Box 015)
      - RG tss. of RG translations from the German poems of Georg Trakl (1887-1914), (65 pp. total)
        Some pub. in Selected Poems: Georg Trakl (Jonathan Cape, 1968), ed. Christopher Middleton.
      - RG ts. of "FIVE VERSIONS OF A TRAKL POEM: 'Geistliche Dammerung'", (5 pp. total)
      - RG ts. of "NOTES TOWARD A PAPER ON THE TRANSLATION OF TRAKL", 1964 - 1965 Fall Term, (20 pp. total)
  - B. University of Iowa/Program in Creative Writing Papers 1966
    - 1. RG ts. of "ASPECTS OF SEMANTIC DENSITY IN THE POETRY OF GEORG TRAKL", 1966 Jan 19, (24 pp. total) (Box 015)
    - 2. RG ts. of "Stones And Water / Water And Stones: What is of value in the poetry of Robert Creeley", 1966 Spring Term, (12 pp. total) (Box 015)
  - C. RG Critical Writings, 1970 - 1998
    - 1. Background Materials re publication of this 1 (Box 015)
      - Barrett Watten ts. letter to RG, re this 1 1970 December, (2 pp. total)
      - BW letter to RG (BW ts.) (re this 1 w/ BW/Carl Gottesman poems 1970 Dec 29), (6 pp. total)
      - BW ts. letter to RG, re this 11970 Dec 31, (3 pp. total)
      - RG ts. letter to Ron Silliman, 1970 Dec 1, (xerox) (2 pp. total)
        Regarding this & that & asking for contribution to this 1 w/ RG poems from. "Fall/Winter Family Home", pub. in Series (This Press, 1978).
      - RG ts. letter to Curtis Faville, 1970 Dec 6, (xerox) (4 pp. total)